i ask for a preview dot slash hiding in
my normal file
then throws like a weird reference link
inside the document doesn't go anywhere
yet you knowing when this happened to
their sneaky
security note
blender
uh... little bit
here's our person here who knows more
than i do
asked the person that orchid then
extensible several has done some wonders
absurd it's pretty powerful also
everyone that's our pre singing sketchup
but they're different kinds of programs
that both read
sketchup is less about the animation
and wonder is more about creating a form
of the year
surcharges
dot
is leaves
the different versions so if you look
around their stuff
and
you could try rebooting virtual machine
you might need to go to the menus and
can lead to heart
three-star
so when you bring it back up
this is coming right up i would suggest
if you can get there and you're actual
recruit from the power button
uh... when you call the invited to a hot
and
and my stuck with the same problem again
people ignore mouse in there
trying to find
virtual machine
soon control to lead
mean power yet
do it for every cent from rainer
it's more restart
fast before
if that fails
and you can always with the whole
windows machine as they did something
windows in its handling of the mountains
and the first they were injured provide
for nineteen is
idea reminder on logging in hype right
on in a way that in your computer gets
recruited by a prior now
what
will have to uh... make sure that we
one thing's ourselves so that if the
uh... burnout became catastrophic
and today were it over more bags for an
official doing
the histogram of the elevation were
gonna look at the uncertainty
as uncertainty is important
saudi using hdlc
five and then delete using that followed
for applauding
than we're gonna dig into the matter
there with the x_ amount
so i know that this is not the most
simple acts and i'll start with
but bear with me and try it
hang in there on the external will do a
lot of it for the last
month annapolis class
and then
by kitchen sink if we can make it to you
there will be playing with shape files
coastlines to go with our medea
and hopefully
year probably epa's cost per player next
class hope we will plot up bounding box
from edited out
an actual shoreline database from g_m_t_
this actually called but g_s_ h_h_s_
so you'll see
the bounding box on a map and you can
see that it makes sense highlight
something about it box that's it for
granted
so start off and kick off by python
remember how to do that logging will do
it again
remember that you can do percent quick
ref
quick ref will
and this would like to bring up
denied chichi
various things
hit enter
you'll be in this list of general
overview of pipe iphone
and you can
use the
therapies and speaks to go down
you can also search in this one with the
flash
for next year shift key
and you kept longer
not important as you can just picture it
but there's logoff logon
log star
park st
won't stop
so it's all talking in their it's also
notes so to log state
and logging has not been activated so
we'd like to starts on walking
log start
put a question mark after it and you can
get some help
more detailed help on log start
and the key thing is that we can say
logmein
so you can call whatever you want
to begin to u percent logs started in
the name logfile moderate
log dash class dash nineteen dot p y
it's logging into a python format
you can pick another date if you like to
see if the name that i chose
hit enter
and it should show you some information
about what he's doing that i haven't we
looked up
all of those things
have discussed re
so could you tell us
we should now see outlawed file speaking
to you remember that you can do an
escalation point to get back to the back
shell
so we can use the head command analogue
clocks
and hit enter
and you will see
beginning of your log file
so it's always good to with these things
to make sure when you're trying to log
something it's important to you
make sure it's actually doing it
uh... definitely myself gone three stuff
got the and i have record a video for
this class i got the end
hate save and i put it back and there
was no audio
so every quarter half an hour video with
no audio
and was there hate bury found
so it's always good to check the head
what u doing works
so that's the basics of logging
there's a panic more that you can do
i walk into that were into something fun
for change we've been really pushing a
lot of uh...
he max and heavy stuff it usually
attract
a really important eitan mah jong
import
n_c_i_ gravity
is a very important module
he has lots of uses in python to hit
enter
if you know the cartoon x casey
you should see a little cartoon about
soared and this is where he describes
living coral
her
so there's that some jokes hiding in
princeton
are at least a little pond so it's not
all serious
the whole his that
create role
here are not that you know
i don't know what's going on
i don't know what i came from
so now we're in trying to quickly go
back through what we did last time
let me get the backloading
so here's the structure what we're gonna
be voting in
health record from last time
we're gonna be loading up the elevation
the meditate up
outlook and a tracking what's she would
never found anything so
everybody knows all about file with the
tracking listen for the delay no and i
will do uncertainty also
i'm is going to go ahead and assume that
that you don't have the file from last
time
and we'll go to section getting back to
where we work
medha w copy that line
and the pace today to get command with a
bang in front of it
to run the show command inside of my
point on some it'll have to jump back
and forth
so there are
though exclamation point hiding
carefully don't click on this
there's active links or in front of the
uh... terminal
so through the you are allen hearing if
a client
can end up with extra files running
around
so you can hit enter
since this is again locally
posted it should be pretty quick
band i believe
we need to uncompressed that
and make sure it's all there so we'll
see
the un's that too
each one impressed tab complete that
file does enter
she go pretty quick
and then you can do in our special to
make sure that you actually have
the file in there and compressed
so here is
our bags from my iphone though the even
now they've got his back probably can
start
working with the gimmick
so let's go ahead and bring in the
models for any today the first one we
need is number line
imports
num pint were also there need
each five pint and then
we need to bring in plotting for math
problem so from that
walked lib
import
hi plot
so the num are part of that and the pipe
up
part of that came in with the dash dash
pile out in the past that i am now
boarding
word out ready to go ahead and load up
about final
source a bag
which we are very well name
equals each five pipe period
capital ap
and you'll get final
footprint c single quotes
and you take the h and just hit tab and
we only have one bag file on the street
recently connections to complete
and press enter
should load up pretty quick
so before we pulled it apart so that
they go through that too much we're
gonna
figure quick reminder of
the fact that i can do you
didn't show this last time with sleeper
bag dot keys
and this works just like a dictionary
so keys is the same thing that works on
dictionary
and newer ones top-level keys that gives
us our bedroom we can then say
so backwards
amarin keys are not
and we get the lower levels of that
waiting to hear list of the keys for
factories and we got
those four guys down here
so let's go ahead and glum
are elevation
publishing equals
bag
backwards
underscoring their
slash
elevation
right cm typos and they can and value so
it's gonna reach in there and grab a
value section out of our elevation
amra double check that with type
elevation
we have a number i dot and delayed
obscured
you can see elevation taught size
looks pretty good
now last time
if we use a elevation
to enter
we had all these one millions that are
the uh...
the data values puttin when there isn't
data epicor selling our trade
and we had this big poorly for acts
four y
and then if each cell was greater than
zero stuff unemployed dot man in there
and there's actually a lot faster
and shorter way to write this
i think if you're beginning its really
confusing
but i'm i show you
i had to listeners it's basically ah...
you can make a boolean test and then
doing assignments
as is pretty fancy stuff
i'm not
holy sure i'm comfortable with it but he
works pretty well so whilst will use it
swiftly elevation
and inside the square brackets
so calibration
greater than zero
equals
num hai
thought and so in
you know it's you'll see the four lubin
comments but this is a outweighed its
really compact circuit i_p_r_ stephanie
a comfortable with it
you could do a lot of manipulations with
matrices very easily
so to be elevation matrix error rate
two t_v_ right
this is the check on each cell so if
that cell is greater than zero
it will ban assigning pastel
an umpire dot man
inferior this actually built a second
matrix that's true and false for
every cell
at use of that
too
figure out when to do that assignment
the documentation is incomprehensible my
opinion from empire
somebody's artistry documentation and
i'd try it
but this will run allot faster
that we we did it before
so if you enter it comes right back
so they're doing a lot of
make you a chance of making seasonal
rains
this is the way through it
yes so in this case
and the bags format they call arbatov a
tree elevation
plan
i'm being lazy
so i didn't go in there and look and see
if
back if this were white our data it
could actually go maybe up on the
shoreline
there's actually some topographic white
are and some of the bags
yeah
there's also that to you
if we look at the histogram in a little
bit you'll see that i guess right
so what i would do typically
i would have looked up intimidated that
one million was the uh... no value
and i would have written something very
specific to that value some delays
probably should have written something
like
crewman
further like that would've been safer
so i could do that to you
an empty lot safer than using zero
that's a great question
sometimes
being lazy you you get away with it
and the time to get there
watch out for ten point numbers
if you try to use he calls for the
floating point number
your chances of getting
what you expect
are pretty small
for important numbers have a lot of
rounding problems with them separate
rice a q two different values of the
same
you might get nailed by a mail tended to
minus seven
so that we have our rate
let's go ahead and start up a plot
those came up
a few classes back were returned on that
map partly
interactive mode
so that we don't have to have the first
show come up and we have to kill the
figures so think hyatt
interactive
always do question mark to get help
not very helpful
but it was a true
more now have to do as show on our first
figure
table lock up the terminal
so now we can go ahead and jj create our
first figure self-pride plot
figure
and should pop up
at this point
and we can save hyatt
plot memory can you thought we have to
access is thirty
majorca tree like a picture and so will
say
i am hit town
cheryl
and in the same elevation
don't do that
i'm a comment that out for a second
do control and then a pound actually won
it
have you guys start using the subplot
feature so we can have
were unhappy uh...
the elevation
and histogram for elevation
the uncertainty in the history of
uncertainty on one figure
says something more like what you do you
have
lotsa plots up if they're all of your
screen they get a little confusing
sifted organize things
will say
five plot dot
in this you'll say the number of
roseanne menorah columns suits you into
and then though
third number is
which
one of those figures counting from the
top left we're going to be in
subplot teaching
and that's now
put us up in the top left hand corner
building a graph
michael back to this
hi plot commands
remove the pound at the front but i had
to enter so before we head to a show
and then it would lock up the terminally
akhil a figure to be gone
so now we have are nice but then a trio
from the top left
and just give you a hint right this is
uh... lovely place up in alaska
and now we can move on to the histogram
so we need to for histogram to convert
to hear a into a hole in the area
and there's probably a lot better ways
to do it then when i came up with here
there's probably another one line and
you can do
so what we're going to you
commands that you did for elevation date
he calls an amana reshape the matrix
into
now when the matrix so will stay in
television
dot reshape
and then you can your question mark
after that
uh... if it's in the middle of it person
doesn't always like to do the question
mark
so if you have a little e_t_a_ equals
that's not going to give you the help
so your television reshape
pool safety
data sequels
and what we do is bring a pass it in
before five th so before it was a
whipping up a
gas to the size which would be a one d
matrix about mine sourcing elevation
size
answer
now just type b_ data and take a peek at
it
and now we have those millions hiding in
there that we don't want
so we need to create a new listed it
doesn't contain any of the cells that
have names on them
sourcing ikeda
barbera list without manzanares
nicky and he left the two square
brackets
and they can say
for hire
range
floated a lengthy of
and them on to say he
the resized
or the reshape so this one
where appreciated from a square
into one long
this size is the total number of cells
so as the whip
anarchy has to wait times the height
this gives fact
to reshape
how many rows and columns
and they can actually be an dimensional
himasa dimensions
so we're gonna give it back
so if there's a for the first to mention
what's my size for the second
emotionless midsize
and so
this is going to have
opens go wit but no height
so the sort of a number of cells
sicily where translate
so if you want to make that square
against
well let's angular you could say
television
not recieved
and then you could say something like
tammy
twenty four hundred or something
whenever the members of the sells for
and i would turn it back into a
rectangle
they're just taking opinion ballistic
out long
all right so
back to work for a bit so therefore i
din range
the white abar
one delay
and then inside there
where they say it
mediator
sobai summary of what did you want felon
there
and we can put a knot in front of it
because we don't want to be
and then there's a
command to tell if it's not a man
and that's going to be numb pie dot is
nam
so that will be num
five-dollar
is neon
so that will return true if this is a
man
wanna foot that because
will want to be true when it's not a man
have the wrong number of parentheses
click or something
so for our ticking range
indeed uh...
cohen
if not
known by
is noon
this is getting really ugly salt
just watch for second like at this rate
and then we'll come back to it
so then once we're there if it's not me
and the most saved
he data
clean dot hands
equals
it's gonna run
this is what i get for not looking over
at the
text next to me on the paper
this is the command banana run and
should be
writes
that's running running running let's
make sure it's
it seems to be happy
in fact the apparel get back to it
as you can see the whole thing it's also
directly in the class notes and or file
you get back to you work files that you
can see it's mostly is named
all right so it's this
right there
that's what it should look like
as cheating by not looking and i paid
for it
so now if we say
control you
get rid of that will say wife
of ikeda
c we got
that so many cells we have left in our
new
anant before we uh...
revisions would say if i can give a
clean
so this is how many actually got rid of
all demands
so we can do is we can say length of
pedido
minus
you needed uh... clean
anticipate tell us how many hands we
actually got rid of it
and this is it a little more command for
either isn't in the note spaces kind
eyes to see
so that's how many
millions we have
will divide up by our toll number cell
length
he data
we have to watch out over and do a
divided coming up
integers uninjured sourcesafe
float
to enter
ninety two percent of that bag
novena
so when you on packed one of these bags
the old version the format didn't do any
compression
most of what your story on the desk with
a bag
was empty space but nothing in it
g
enough for you
yes arm if you change
discovery here at the range
if you make a man called explains
to have uncovered
will create an actual rate
at this point it's not worth worrying
about
you can get a lot to answer
i'm trying not to get fancy
especially for if you're beginning
accurate code that you won't follow
that'll be really cool and fun
but i'd rather stick with stuff that
here better chance of
old in terms of this factors down here
there's there's lots of ways you can do
this
like as he's always been there for the
for the first one to deceptive
bonanza that
went from the other values
there was more for ways to do that
with the probably come up with private
sector released
so let's go ahead and build a histogram
so please save
pipeline
subplot
scope yourselves
so to do with our dimensions than ever
to move on to number two
simply choose in a row
hit enter
conferred finer figure ever hear we now
have a magical second figure on the top
plate
and now we can say
for histogram
you can see he
here
clean
pins equals
one hundred
so this is going to make
a hundred different things that are
histograms
and we'll hit enter
and so now we've got
is a nice figure thats
for me i wish came with every bag right
away you've got a little plot showing
you what your data looks like
so you can see there's like sandeep
areas in the middle of these uh...
these patches
and you can see their data runs from
minus fifty meters that's fifteen years
city state dept any positive numbers if
you say elevation negative is down
so minus fifty elevation
bout minus
hundred mediators
so it's actually fairly deep in this
area
next terms ship
not d by the ocean standards
so now it covered the uh... elevation
from before
now it's time to jump into certainty
you might not know what to expect in
terms of uncertainty for the data
i certainly didn't and i've definitely
some funky in search of peace as some of
the earlier bags
let's go ahead and load up that
uncertainty into a variable
not the best variable wings i wasn't
being very creative just wanting to
bring that up
so go ahead and set uncertainty
report of the bag
or rather the hat
within carol
into the bags in the square bracket
single quotes slash
backwards
slash uncertainty
dot value
and you can type
type of uncertainty
always good to make sure everything is
happy
we also
to change a poll that you can type who's
with us on it
and you'll see all of your data
so hopefully uncertainty is hiding here
somewhere
so this is not
a terrible
representations of your chosen and the
rain
chose the within the height
former elements it's afloat thirty
two-bit
how many flights which is ten megabytes
survived today's computers there has not
too much data
so here we're looking at concession
looking at uncertainty
that was the commands that iran
so let's take a peek
so we had a shape we got back from the
whose but we can also do it from
uncertainty
dot shape
so here's our
width and height
we cast at the minimum
a forceful effort out the parentheses
it's a function
modest about yourself
we
or that you are prints these the minimum
value of the uncertainty is point g_-one
aids
i don't have a good intuitive feel for
what points do you need one uncertainty
means
then we can you max and we get that same
one million
we have the same problem with me and
said we had before with the television
so we can remove those who can say
certainty
square brackets and it's a uncertainty
amma take a wild guess
greater ban
one thousand
i'm pretty sure uncertainty runs in the
zero to one range
equals
numbed by
union
yes we've got
in the note they use krugman won votes
right thirteen thousand since i was
brought up his team
trouble before
theatrical is really quickly
into let's give that applauds so they
can actually see what's in there
school say pipe locked in a reviewer
subplot again
and we want to go so as to bite you
again
this is one up here in the top what to
you and operate angry cabrini overhear
starting to you
and for the better part we don't want
for ground
so let's plot
had fought
anonymity the image show
and uncertainty
so hopefully
i hit enter
we'll have a view of uncertainty
uncertain about the uncertainty
before up there we go
i don't have a good intuitive feel for
uncertainty at work for the too much
this is at least a view of the
uncertainty in like one of my early
fears with
multimedia and out of the bags is that i
thought lots and lots of data with the
same uncertainty and i wasn't sure
why that was the case because
i definitely that there are areas with
greer high sensitivity
candidate and look at it
of closing the raw data
figure because he is totally different
we have a couple actions
we can also rerun arming
and max we can say
uncertainty
the men shouldn't change because we
didn't fill with the low end of things
reports say the man throws off
the men in the max
where i have to wait for our histogram
to see what the range of uncertainties
are
all right so we need to go through and
do the same exact building of
wendy arrayed without manzanares
so we can say
you data equals uncertainty
talk reshape
watch out for my tabs again if you
notice i hit tab twice in there
they're sixty three three times
uncertainty
dot science so wendy array
and they should give us
when the array
that's what i didn't notice
yes
and our decreed an empty
you do that clean
really go fill that up with a four week
again
so for
on a
range
length of
you do you know
not
num polly
his name
time is really bad inside of this kind
of stuff
sorry about that
medida so behind
and it's in the notes in
in here so please scroll down
you can
if you try to fall summing don't falls
creat there for a minute follow
the stuff in that word file
actually works for sure
we'll see
you
diva clean append
applied
throughout the day value is not
and then we want to come out a right
answer
appliances runs
and now we should be less tied to use
data
clean just a quick view of it
and you'll see all values
going through their for two hundred
thousand-plus
it's a great way to fill your screen up
with job
stuart you i his dream about
pipe lots
stood against the two to further within
uh... the rows and columns of our plot
and then
we're now on number four
remember again that
i bought falls matlab so we count from
one not zero like most of tight on if we
hit
enter after that
we now have a blank one for number four
it's a pie
use data
and so now we have our first do you
really
of what the range of
syper i don't like it without you pins
sold to you
began pins
equals one hundred
i'm eddie braving type a c l_ a_
wat steel and hope it doesn't wipe out
all of them
so take a good look before destroy
everything on time
i didn't like that this bt perhaps you
can keep adding onto a graphing
searching in the scale
them if they see that it goes from point
to two point five percent somewhere in
that neighborhood
and enter
hopefully that works clears yet
i got lucky
having a metaphor
so our reporter histogram
and for the better
so here we can see it
we have a nice history showing us that
we have a couple of values that are
in certain key is point nine
i'm guessing that
hello uncertainty probably means you
know more about the data and has
answered it gets high that data you know
less about
that value here
you're not sure ok sunny value
now hopefully your other classes because
i'm not gonna give using tuition here
by the end of year
i would hope that you have if you look
at this histogram you have a good sense
of how good or bad tactic
height don't
number but i think i've ever done has
had uncertainty in it
most my most him work was done before
cuban think like that worked on
i don't have a sense of that
i can't really help you with that
you can ask some of the notebooks are
some of the other staff who worked a lot
of uncertainty
get a better sense of
of what that means
and welcome to crowd that figure in
children and say was i mean
so now we're gonna go from the land of
obvious pretty pictures in the land of
axa mellon angle brackets
figure by the pretty picture
different pretty picture hopefully by
the end of class
but no more previous dimitri
please go for about an inbox
normally when you do a plot
pablo comment here that you should label
everything
were cheating here rally long anything
so
please don't do that in your figures for
class
and for your work
now we're going to accent no
i think they're going to be a little
hard on your
your brains here
in terms of throwing in a lot of
material
so just write to you
feel for accent on this class
we'll see who see it a little bit before
will see a whole lot more
as we go through it
amra show you some actually really
advanced
techniques
because that acrylic exim l
without those advanced techniques
is a pain
because parsing tax is never very fine
reload up that meta data amber any you
something called
expound
to search inside of x_ amount of execs
ml really easy because you can't go
crappy tag you want how that data
and use it
now although at cases and figuring out
all the details of special things can
get hard but the easy cases are really
hopefully fairly easy
and you'll see here will be able to pull
out
the bounding box for
that bag will be able to pull the title
in the abstract fairly easily
and then we can write ourselves a little
came out which is the type of action now
animal though that i think it will work
and you'll be able to see
the bounding box for this
chart right on a map
semi air photos from google earth of the
area
executed
gold the purpose of this though
the purposes external
so we've got lots of different ways of
storing data like is jeff by the way of
storing things
exim elyse text format
that's supposed to be human readable
in air quotes
in extreme of human readable stuff
got angle brackets and things called
tags around difference
uh... variables he'd like to store
that makes it easier for machines
departs
and pull out the sex between those tags
and has a lot of a tree structure
kinda like this
and in there
will be storing a lot of variables and
to be able to access them and build up
the structures and have a p_d_a_
structures three oh three stains
is one of many formats that are similar
it just happens to be probably the most
popular one right now
that's or about high-level view of x_
amount
in terms of
when it's used for sort of data storage
format that
you could pick it up
look at it as a human have a chance of
reading some of it unlike if you pick up
a stiff by file new look
looked in there
it's going to be just binary star
where to go through looking at these
files and hope we'll start to see the
what and how all of them
by example
so first we are bringing a model that
were used to parse x_ amount i'll use a
library called l maximo
i tend to like it more than the ones
that come with python because they tend
to be a little bit more skier
so will say from l x amount imports and
raise the heat treat or elementary
there's lots of different styles of 'em
ways departs x_ amount
peachtree way seems to be fairly easy
compared to the other ones
ways to my payment
and let's go ahead and load up that meta
data like we did last time
and here i've been
mixed in veg or no we did last time
in the back format bihac were committed
stores the medicare has
an array of strings that are wife
one as opposed to a string of one for
the tax i had managed to concentrate
discussion on the uh...
napster
bag mailing list yesterday over this
them in a case study in there
we now have a meta data status in
mid-air
describe the first fifty characters will
do in the race twice on that
and you'll see
this little string right here is the
beginning of
annexin all document
so here is that
an angle bracket a question mark
x_ amount version
and one point you know
and that is a jump into some
things called namespaces that we won't
get into you
we're going to be more than for today
so now what that may be a taxed
now we want turn into an elementary
before we do that let's save this out so
we can pull it up any max and have it on
the side of the reference
so what we can do is we can create uh...
file the writings for the sake of equals
open
and then the metab backup to replace bag
with x_ amount
comma and then when the user strings
just interviewed says gramm
for writing
enter so that we have
never filed or writing
config out dot right
and cops that are meta data dot text
hit answer and then we can close out dot
close
car
we've now written that made it to the
desktop acumen howard stern show
you should see
here
are mediterranean to cadets
we can tell
fear to report we play with the editor
we can tell the editor of t_v_ did u
agee max clients no wait
something like that with an escalation
point in front of it
or you could say addicts
so i'm gonna say edits dash x means
please do not execute this
because normally when you're working and
i python tries to execute anything that
you look at it
each one tab
x_ amount
and the press enter its gonna pop up
this filing max
and is this a waiting for imax
he noticed on the bottom control expound
is the
character that you can use
telling that this is don soviet control
x
and then i'd pipeline gets to run again
so that would end up
our external file on there
and if you go back here we can actually
do something
that makes it a lot nicer remember life
and went through all sorts of crazy max
kaminsky s
so if it didn't load
and he says he may ask why i can't find
socket
happy for the server
if you go and your team acts
and to you
meta
acts
server
dash
start
they should start the mac server mode
that we didn't have to supple while back
a few blocks up from her dot you max
then
you need to do that again
all day for a year will save
mena acts
server start
in my case i just restart the server
and they should be able to come back
here and do that and again
let's go ahead
or you get it if you're still working on
that i met you another one or read
morale we did that replaced them an x_
where place last time
mctiernan pipeline i think you'll find
it looks a lot simpler
so we can say out to you
recreate second file will say uh... open
hampton said bring us a try
supreme phones exactly here
this is really missed three and will
skip the other example
and need to open it for writing
and what we can do is say out too dot
rates
and we can say that maybe the file
would you really don't want to do that
so i can hit control k
control you'll wipe out that line start
over
so you get out of that
again i i come back to you i see acts
and the hash or pound character
let's do that replacement before
wikipedia and the records
and twenty one in between
if we look at this text of the state
meta data metaxas
bizarre replace commands
and we can replace one string with
another
so what time we replaced the angle
brackets
with a new line in between
so please you
angle brackets now do nothing but we
want to put slash and
any strings
in i thought i'm going to many other
programming language of a backslash and
the letter and
represents a new one
if you hit
it looks pretty tedious
you'll see lots of squash and is that
doesn't really feel like very much
but if you do the print in front of that
if you run the sprint
the prints will actually evaluate those
new lines you know what she calls a new
line to being employed
so hit return on this one
and hopefully
you'll see
negative looks more like what we had
formerly max before
presenter
now it's
one per line
you can see all of the fermented in
there
so what we're right back out to the out
cubes with the arabs to dot right
so one thing we can do you
control you wipes out the wine and will
say
house too dot right
duvet paste
amrita right that replaced taxed
into a file
and sake i wish to dot close
analyst as shown
and now we have another file
strike three right here
and we can say and it's
dash acts
each one one five
strike three now
and that books
more like what we wanted to have
so i'm gonna go ahead and do the control
acts
pounds to say i'm done anything yet
and we now have arrived by phone back
so that we have
texted you can look at
and won't be able to brad things like
title right out of
there's x_ amount file
so we need to do is use l x amount too
parse this x_ amount file and then they
can use this expat search thingy
that i have really explain very well
to go in there and grab out tags
so what we can do is to say
please go into this document
go find me the first i don't
and grab whatever it between taxes just
give it back to me as a string
lingo in and say
i'd like
gate please
i'd like the abstract at like
the ecological on hugh downs
began formed by name without having to
search through the whole tax
and he was angle brackets and things
like that
let's put this and go back to my or go
to trial
and the way
we ask
elementary to parcel data is right up
here
use heat remote you want to be safe
constrain any past amended tax
because often doesn't stop and then
abortion is this actual sneaky step on
the end
once it's done the first thing it's
built some will object
and we need to get the route noted that
three so we can look at it
so i'm gonna go ahead and
one that commands
had trouble with writing the files
don't worry about that we don't need the
files for the rest of class
reach into here and we're gonna
ignore those fathers start pulling
things out there until two a rich
people's petri
from straying
metal give the medicare tax
right there
and them or ask you for that kept rooms
tree
to enter
and we have this grouping set
don't worry about the details but this
is
a representation of that file but we can
then ask him
for data fields from
so let's try
grabbing the title
fool say
equals
groups dot xpath interact path is a
search engine built into x_ amount
it's got some funky syntax
slash slash is the representation of the
start other document
so it tries to treat it like of
filesystem
so it's like the unix or let x
filesystem where it's going to have
first levels that
will do a search for title
so what we've done appear
the xpath
search tool
this is the top level of your document
star says any path
and go fine either first title
back inside
westphal
depression listing all the elements if
we'd just type
title and press enter
turns out it eyeliner it wasn't looking
for the first one it was their return
all of them three analysts
in this case you don't want i don't
and so we have a list of one
so it'll give us a list of every single
title it was in there for the little
ones
the square brackets
tell us that we have a list
alma title
gonna really horrible number
is just kinda huntley but
this is given us a list of one title if
there were more of them there'll be more
things
airplanes
and it's a half section no dot
it looked like the and i'm not talking
him
out you can do that kind of stuff
there's a different kind of interface
for that is not very fine
so we can definitely go through most all
the task
here we can just load up and you know
we have example at the spec looks like
i think if you want to get the final out
of it
the abstract
all right so let's pull out but i don't
from that list
they really want the first ones will say
title equals title
zero
so crap that first one out
throughout the state title
we have and elements not the most fun
boats saved
title
period
and then hit cap
there's ton of stuff in here
the ones we want
are these tags inside the angle brackets
and text is a text inbetween
so ignore everything else in just a tag
so the tag is titled not too surprising
hussein text
barest uh... actual title text of this
bag
yes option
what this does
with x_ amount we've gotten madonna
search we get back to list of
will sections of arsenal document and
we've in this case will have one section
and then you can go into that section
worked with him
faintly hear text is very simple there
just text in front of a note
isn't mister curse instruction because
we down and
like some of them do
we've gotten back
representation just this part of the
document
so if we asked for
something else like
c_i_d_
if we ask for this country here
we would get back something also
contains date vitale
you get back to school block it
from children
archery before complicated
so don't don't stress about this too
much as when you see an example and see
that
once you get snow that's cool
preaching and grabbing you know that you
need
can be very easy
understand the whole document and what's
there
uh... and certainly not
and braiding complicate xpath is are
definitely account that some people have
so let's go ahead and try to make this
title command into something that she
grows in graft i totally want
typical backup to our xpath
really what we want to deal with we're
gonna get back to list mourner grab the
first on the back
so will to uh...
grab the first one
from their and we really didn't want
back is that there was this element that
we didn't really
it gives a horrible printing that's an
element in some evil number
we want to get the dot
so that's the command we actually want
to have
robert i don't
service a title now
we just have a tax for title so if
you're building it
uh... plot
and you're entitled with the title
well actually don't want to use this
title costano non-degree title
but that's how we pulled out a tag close
to a couple more
let's try the abstract
so if we look at our documents here
if i do a control ads abstracts
we can see that
our abstract
free here
that the testimony of the crab al
so if we say abstract
equals bruise dot
xpath
and now you have an example the copy
from above
so slash slash star
anywhere in the document give me all the
abstracts
and abstract so this text link here
the abstract is this tag
right there who want to find
we want to get the first one square
brackets in zero
and dot taxed
socket enter
cross your fingers
and now type abstract
if all goes well we see the abstract of
our document
and last class
there was some question about gates
what is the data pierced a two thousand
eight
when the survey was done in two thousand
seven
there was a catch
that there was some confusion there
that's the date
i believe that the
the fact file was created
so survey was done in two thousand and
seven
as you can see down here in the abstract
and this date appear with the date the
bag was created not dictate that there
was collected
so it's one of those things where
if you're really getting into the stuff
i would recommend reading up on the bag
specification and getting all the
details about all the parts
because seen to date
he can lead you down the wrong road if
you get the wrong assumption about what
a field means
there's not really enough information to
understand all attacks and document
i definitely a bit by some wrong
assumptions
secular cert
title and abstract
if we want to get the longitude inside
in the control absent allele in g_ to
search
insider document is actually
that bounding box
for the tax
remember control lessening maxis search
either so i was like when the notes that
were here
let's uh...
let's take a quick ph
yeah there is a typo there i was missing
a single quote
so you guys can a for following
directions
and i get an astronaut
three directions to write
so let's go grab are
bounding box cordis in the same strategy
sourcing x-men
chuck back here
sourcing x-men equals float because i
want to turn that strengthen number into
an actual number
rich dot xpath
start my search during
slash slash star so anywhere
balance
long g
tumi opportunities for typos
and again we want to grab the first one
that we find
uh... that list
and we want to tax
then remember that
we to close that parentheses so i think
that
this press him on right now matches the
swan over here
for private concert
index list out of range that means i
type something wrong
oranges and this belongs to
and have a better support advancement
i now have our minimum maxwell u
i don't know what happens when you go
over the dateline
anchorage unified a dragon spans fiat
national dateline and see what happens
you'll probly have the will come
crashing down on you
so we can also you can just get pcs
accused profited tight
so i'm gonna grab those guys
medic w
and i'm going to pay xd
so now for tycoons
who enter
and if you look down here
we have
are bounding box
now this is a really important check
because some of the early bag writing
software
didn't you browning boxes correct links
that you tried to just
demanded a it's a go figure out working
lies
you got one of the bag that was put up
on and do you see
was coming from central canada on land
covering about having province
so it's great to write your own kotecha
stuff
to make a little bit elevation of it so
what we're doing now
if try to make a google earth came out
that actually put this on the glow
intend them to us
won't probably make it will get calls
let me start off with the limit each you
guys
that's happening language inside a pipe
bomb where you can basic reader file
will parts that are missing in it
for example to trying to create a
metadata file
you could cut out like the title on the
abstract and you want to put in your own
icon gives you a way to take some of the
file like that
and to writing variables
by name
uh... the tip of the way that people do
this
before it was you say like
hello percent d
for a number
world
and then percent analysts
mystified
one-two-three-four
and it would then use these percents and
their numbers and floats and strings
take the values of this list and you
have to make sure that the number of
them matched up
i think this is
really error prone campaign
so i'm gonna show you that he didn't
styled and if you're using hydro if
you're in or person
hide your uses python two point five
this feature starting python two point
six
so if you're a pager user i'm sorry this
is going to work for you
and you have to encourage the pointer
authors to be the upgrade tree
uh...
but let's go ahead and give it a go
and will start
for here so the way it works
and there is another type of my notes
uh... missing another
single quote which they seem to like to
get away today so way it works
value
so you put your very baldwin's in curly
braces inside of a string
and then on that string you call the doc
format methadone
and it will then
process that string and replace variable
so go ahead and answer
and he should get an error
you get here
if you search for it
plot the bounding box
to control that's plot va
and you can find it in control of school
wrap-around
so you know what
i see that ah...
i have another bug here
so how i bumped a character and i
causative there's a status is comin
trade here
that cause the export mode to not export
this entire section
and so i think this was the helping on
the keyboard an inopportune time and
didn't notice that change something
it was there when i exported handful
that not to export this action
i highly recommend sticking with the or
file
during class
and even then
he might have trouble
here after class i will bring exported
would have taken care
so let's get back to our a string here
now we got rid of those troubles
and what you can answer is
my value equals
and you could say hello
world
bathurst ring
animal stuff
whatever you put in there
into that space
we can also a place that strength with
the number two one two three point four
five
and it will stop the number in there
rather than having to remember percent d
percent abdomen counting
one-two-three-four throughout your
strength
you can do this in call things by name
which i'd find it much easier to follow
young six months after you've written a
code to come back to me
you just booked for the variable name
and then you look at that place
so it's been a couple minutes and get
better at that
switch over to our x-men and
circular in our bounding box if we do
x-men
format
x-men would be better
x-men
enter
and went into that variable
pulled it out of our
local variables
report without
if you uh...
control our x-men
he control are going to keep searching
back
so we grabbed x-men with this command
play here
who's gonna control c
sadat run actually going to run again
now we can also do you mow for variables
the same time
so to take that command
and replace
tns wimax
than we have to go into our
tremors for format in the pacific value
for wimax
now i'm not sure when that for example
is not my notes because i realize it's
confusing
we can make this whatever we want
so we can set that you want to
this might be a little more
obvious what's going on
so what you've done as you said a
variable
people some value
and that name that was on the leftover
here is put into the
terrible on the story
enter
and it's now stuff in there
you can use the same
variable for both
because they want max equals wimax
animal cause inside this trend that why
max terrible to have that valued wimax
outside
and throws us a little confusing
thicknesses
vision inc
specified
eyes
if you if you wanna carefully format
numbers like fourteen points and whatnot
all kinds of extra stuff to be able to
do that
you'll have to go read the webpage and
go through it here which is that if the
default behavior and everything and try
to keep it simple
so it's just got a call
we actually doing is equivalent of
during this call
s_ t_ r_ wimax
getting straight back
ethical and what it's doing
you can get really fancy like this
it's got some really powerful features
haven't explored and too much
what you get is a little hard to reach
times
so let's say
we're gonna skip the barry marks one of
the show you
the really great command and skip the
the middle part you can read the notes
if we say vocals
this is
a function devil actually
created dictionary of
everything in your local which you get
back with whose civic center
annual c
cold beer
don't do that
we've got a lot of data loading up right
now like
thirty megabytes of data loaded into our
locals
and life is really bad
and so with that i think we're in
declared today died
every time they were in locals which is
the last couple concluded
if if they call that day that i will not
in their and it's going to make a secure
call
so do that
and it's time to time class for today
that spectacular
how would you think that what
so in the notes ido bien gets you
i have a template that's a came off i
only say that on desk and you can do
and open command of a file
icici going
which is going on here
so here is a sample of came out
that i've got to sit back into a file
and right here
i called open about template
dot read
paulette all into a variable and then
we can and say
came hours or template doc format star
star locals is a special trip to pull
pulls into format
and magically you have a camel file
with everything filled out that you work
for one thing
origin a couple more examples of this
and by the end of semester
i'd like you guys to be hopefully able
to
right out may create template for
medicare
fight over values allison
and then fill out the meta data so that
you can actually create your own
navigator for some other kind of fear
that you are interested in
that's the goal that were aiming towards
here
is being able to build these template
files
so if you've gone through i had so many
which is really complicated you can
builders of a template
but in the curly braces for things like
you know author dayton
all our stuff
use papon to generate all that data
and then you call this dot format
boom it shows all the two together
and you have
ballad i assume that data
that you can then send-off and gbc leads
the major data
that's the goal what we're aiming for
and work was good ways away from that
but we're getting there
so will keep goin through this will be
some more examples of
reaching into axa melville than came out
you'll see a lot of different versions
of x_ amount hopefully it'll start
becoming more familiar
rescue costs
hot not too much snow
no it's pretty permissive on status of
the few places where it has to have some
sort of space but doesn't care what kind
of space